Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
help coaches, trainers, and mentors
scale their businesses, get more
clients, and make more money online.
Now, today I want to talk about how you
don't need to be the one to do
everything yourself, and you shouldn't
be. In our businesses, we need to learn
about how to remove ourselves from the
business, how to not be the one that's
in the weeds of everything. Your genius
is in training, mentoring, creating
content, and everything else is not
stuff that you need to necessarily be
doing. Now, you need to understand how
to do all the different aspects in your
business, but to be the one physically
doing everything isn't the best part
about it. And you might be listening to
this now saying, "Well, Jeremia, I don't
have a I don't have a budget to be able
to afford to hire other people." I'm
going to address that. You might say,
"Well, listen, I'm the one that can do
it all best myself." I understand that
as somebody who was a perfectionist,
recovering perfectionist who always
wanted to do everything myself, I can
tell you it's not the best thing to do
and that it's better to be able to find
the right people that can help you. Now,
number one, there's a great website that
I love that's just absolutely amazing.
Can't recommend it enough called online
jobs.ph PH and I have on this site I
have hired
numerous people that have worked with me
on here. Let me pull it up if you're
watching the YouTube version of this.
It's a job board for people virtual
workers in the Philippines. And so I
personally have a a video editor that
helps me. I have somebody who helps me
do my web stuff, who helps me do my uh
Facebook ads. I have a bookkeeper
who helps me uh with bookkeeping as
well. And I'm even looking and exploring
possibly bringing in somebody who knows
how to do uh copywriting. That'd be
amazing in my business. And so here's
the thing is that I've been in this
industry a long time, but
to have the life that I want to live,
to be able to accomplish the things that
I want to accomplish,
to put together
the the the goals that I have, I don't
need to be the one doing everything
physically doing everything. It's better
if I can find people that I can
outsource and pass off and hand off
certain tasks and roles to
just so much better that way overall.
Okay. And so what you want to do is you
want to be able to figure out, okay, how
can I remove physically being the one
that pulls the levers and does all this
stuff and and even learning how to find
skilled people that you can outsource
certain things to even certain aspects
of. Okay, you can come up with the
ideas, you can start to ide ideiate.
Eventually, it's good to outsource even
some of the idea creation as well. And
we talked about now that we have
artificial intelligence, AI can help us
do like 80 to 90% of a lot of the stuff
that needs to be done, but you still
need some physical human beings doing
stuff. And so having people in the
Philippines help us out with that type
of stuff is great. Now, how do you know
how to hire people? Well, again, I'm
going to go back to AI.
You can use AI to say, "Hey, I'm hiring
somebody on online jobs.ph. I want you
to create me a job listing on XYZ roll.
Detail out all the details that I need
to put in the listing and use chat GPT
03 or above to be able to do this. At
the time of this recording, 03 is the
best one that can do this." And so,
yeah, this is going to really help you a
lot in your ability to reach the type of
clients that you want. And
the cost of this is amazing. You can
hire people from $3 to $10 an hour to do
things. And and you can negotiate and
say, "Hey, I only want to pay for 10
hours of work a month, 5 hours a week."
And you might be like, "Wow, like
they'll actually do that." Yes, you they
will actually be willing to work
part-time
for you at whatever rate, however many
hours that you want to be able to get
stuff done. Now, everybody on the site
on online jobs says, "Oh, I want to be
for full-time and all that." It's almost
always negotiable.
And so, when you make a job listing,
you're going to get hundreds of
applications.
Maybe less than 10 of those are going to
be like really good. And what I like to
do is I like to have to where they have
to say a specific word in the response
to put it in the subject line. And I
only look at the people who do that.
Only about half of the people who apply
are going to actually do the thing that
you've said. If you put it right at the
very bottom of your listing of what to
do, it shows that they read through the
whole thing. They actually read through
it. And then what I'll do is I will pay
attention to, okay, what is their
experience? What have they done before?
What is their portfolio? And I really
start to become very
I'm scrutinizing is this person up to
par with what I want. Are they are they
have they accomplished at this level? do
they have the skill to I'm not
trying to find just the cheapest option
but I will rank it by okay what is their
cost
and then what is the skills that they
have
can they did they actually listen to my
directions in the in the job listing and
these are things that chat GPT you can
even tell chat GPT to do this okay
So,
we don't need to be the ones that are
doing everything. And often times
we end up being that way because
we think that
it's better if I'm the one doing
everything. That it's better if I have
my hands in the weeds of all the stuff
that's going on in my business. That my
hands are in the weeds of making sure
that I'm accomplishing everything. Now,
it's it's not always best sometimes some
industries, some businesses, it's not
always best to hire VAS and stuff in the
Philippines for things, but when it
comes to your marketing, when it comes
to in a coaching business,
I think it's a great thing that you can
do. I have an admin always that's
usually in the United States that helps
me. Somebody that's that is uh
trustworthy that can be kind of in the
weeds of my billing and my
administration and customer service. But
for everything else, I outsource it to
people that are in the Philippines that
I can hire, that are really good, that
are legit at what they do. And that
helps me accomplish the things that I
want to accomplish. That helps me get
done the stuff that I want to get done.
And it's amazing how much you can get
done when you truly set out to say,
"Okay, I I don't need to be the one
doing everything. I'm willing to go find
some good people
to get actually get accomplished what I
need to get accomplished.
I'm willing to make a little bit of an
investment. And can I tell you this? If
you're like, "Well, I don't want to
invest money into doing this." If you've
been procrastinating for 6 to 12 months
to get something done in your business
because it's too hard,
it's going to be worth it to hire
somebody for a hundred bucks.
Because if you think about that, $5 an
hour times that's maybe 20 hours to get
it done for a gig. It might only be a
hundred bucks.
And that $100 is literally going to
progress you forward in your business.
And so, can I tell you this? It's time
to stop making excuses.
It's time to stop justifying why you
can't move forward and start actually
moving the needle forward in your
business and remove yourself from having
to do all this stuff. Focus on your
genius. Your genius is connecting,
communicating, talking, sharing. What is
the stuff inside of you that you're
sharing with people that that only you
can share that is going to help
move the needle forward for other people
as a coach, as a mentor, as a content
creator, and then pass off all the other
stuff to others so that you don't have
to be the one doing all the work all the
time. All right, listen.
This is how you build a business and
you're going to thank me later when you
do this and I can't wait to see the
results that come out of it. All right,
grow your life everybody. We'll talk
soon. Have a good one.
[Music]
[Applause]